The Greatest Break-Up Story Ever Told.
Sita Sings the Blues is a animation, drama, music film directed by Nina Paley.
Utilizing the 1920s jazz vocals of Annette Hanshaw, the epic Indian tale of exiled prince Ramayana and his bride Sita is mirrored by a spurned woman's
contemporary personal life, and light-hearted but knowledgeable discussion of historical background by a trio of Indian shadow puppets.
Sita, played by Reena Shah.
Rama, played by Debargo Sanyal.
Sita (singing), played by Annette Hanshaw.
Narrator, played by Aseem Chhabra.
Narrator, played by Bhavana Nagulapally.
Narrator, played by Manish Acharya.
Sita Sings the Blues is a 2008 American animated musical romantic comedy-drama film
written, directed, produced and animated by American artist Nina Paley.
It intersperses events from the Ramayana, light-hearted but knowledgeable discussion of historical background by a trio of Indian
shadow puppets, musical interludes voiced with tracks by Annette Hanshaw and scenes from the artist's own life.
The ancient mythological and modern biographical plot are
parallel tales, sharing numerous themes.
The film explores themes of jazz, san francisco,
california, cat, suspicion, hinduism.
The tone is emotional.